route conditions like we always
do it‘s getting worse around the
front range so
I think the I-25 corridor has
gone up another notch into
extreme drought.
Had to zoom out, use a different
model. The HRRR model that I
normally show here did not have
And that does show pretty thick
plumes up here and a light
amount of smoke around Colorado.
72% up to 75% for precipitation.
and coverage statewide, which is
what we were expecting.
seven inches of rain with that
storm a couple nights ago so but
it was spotty
Today‘s excessive moisture, it‘s
really precipitation,
So we do have a little chance of
mainly wind
eastern plains but nothing
really close to Denver and
Longmont like that.
continue chance of convection
for Saturday it‘s really in the
mountains
Maybe a strong or two just down
to I-25 area
stationary front draped along it
is cooler out there low 80s so
kind of nice
with the potential for heavy
flooding rains with
thunderstorms.
Temperature day and night 60 and
90 record high 104 is on August
1st, 2008
2, that‘s the record low for all
of July, on the 31st and 8th.
the next day 1995 I‘ll go back
take a look at the next week
Monday through
the moisture is back, so.
But it is tropical storm force.
We‘ll look at that at the end.
Let‘s put this in motion
ridge in the west and it‘s just
going to move over the weekend
over us
pressing convection and moving
the moisture a little further
west and then by Monday it
again into Colorado all week
long so you can see the south
winds here then west
winds around the high and then
get to the end of next week it
jogs back to the four
winds so moisture has to travel
further to get to us and beyond
the end of the third or fourth
of august
front actually coming down. So
we‘ll see that in just a second.
So we do have that front keeping
it cool east of the Rockies on
Thursday. That pushes away.
here recovers quickly the next
day but here we are up to
Thursday and it is still every
afternoon
Some drifting off into the
plains,
Let‘s look at precipitable
water. It is just very rich. We
have a lot of moisture
And then into next week, the
moisture is there.
Initially, I can kick off some
good thunderstorms.
Saturday, we drop to the 40s and
30s.
makes it hard to get good
thunderstorms but by Monday good
moisture starts
in and there you got some
yellows with the 50s and 62
points by midweek so yeah lots
of good
in the West. So monsoon stuff
just gets kind of cut off.
Arizona‘s still going